We've been expecting you.
Silent Hill is a horror, mystery film directed by Christophe Gans.
Rose, a desperate mother takes her adopted daughter, Sharon, to the town
of Silent Hill in an attempt to cure her of her ailment.
After a violent car crash, Sharon disappears and Rose
begins a desperate search to get her back.
She descends into the center of the twisted reality of a town's terrible secret.
Pursued by grotesquely deformed creatures and townspeople stuck in permanent purgatory, Rose begins to
uncover the truth behind the apocalyptic disaster that burned the town 30 years earlier.
Rose Da Silva, played by Radha Mitchell.
Christopher Da Silva, played by Sean Bean.
Sharon / Alessa, played by Jodelle Ferland.
Cybil Bennett, played by Laurie Holden.
Dahlia Gillespie, played by Deborah Kara Unger.
Officer Thomas Gucci, played by Kim Coates.
Silent Hill is a 2006 supernatural horror film based on
the video game series published by Konami.
Directed by Christophe Gans and written by Roger Avary, it is the
first installment in the Silent Hill film series.
The film stars Radha Mitchell, Sean Bean, Laurie Holden, Deborah Kara Unger,
Kim Coates, Tanya Allen, Alice Krige and Jodelle Ferland.
Its plot follows a mother who, after her daughter mentions the eponymous town while sleepwalking and goes missing
upon entering it, uncovers dark secrets within and survives dangerous forces while searching for her.
After attempting to gain the film rights to Silent Hill for five years, Gans sent a video interview to
Konami explaining his plans for adapting it and how important the games were to him.
Konami awarded him the film rights as a result, and he and
Avary began working on the script in 2004.
Avary used Centralia, Pennsylvania as inspiration for the town.
Principal photography began in April 2005 and lasted three months with an estimated $50
million budget, and was shot on sound stages and on location in Ontario, Canada.
Most of the monsters encountered were played by professional
dancers, while a minority were created with CGI.
Silent Hill was released theatrically in Canada on April 21, 2006, by Alliance Atlantis and in
France on April 26 by Metropolitan Filmexport, grossing $100.6 million worldwide.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics upon release,
although retrospective reviews have been more favorable.
A sequel, titled Silent Hill: Revelation, was released in October 2012, while a third film, Return to
Silent Hill, was released in January 2026, with Gans returning as writer-director.
The film explores themes of hotel, pedophilia, child abuse, monster, suffering.
The tone is lighthearted and dark and mind_bending.